

# **Bernardita Roxanna DATO BALANJIU**Penampang, Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, EAST MALAYSIA

Telephone: + (60) 12 839 3809 (Malaysia – Mobile)

Email: <u>bernieroxanna@gmail.com</u>

#### **Profile**

More than 12 years of experience in the hospitality, tourism and education consultancy industries. Good computer skills in Microsoft Office applications and UBS Accounting program, Salesforce CRM and OSCAR program. Proven abilities in HR, administration, learning and development, customer service and interpersonal, management and analytical skills

#### **Achievements**

- Manage and implement HR & Administration of Aquatica Aquarium & Discovery Centre Sdn Bhd as part of the new management team
- Successfully coordinated, organized and managed IDP Education's Exhibitions at hotels in Kota Kinabalu for over 100 visitors
- Successful in representing IDP Education Pty Ltd and various Australian, USA, Canada & UK institutions in various local school and institutions education fairs and other educational fairs and events
- Successful in maintaining a good relationship with various Australian, USA, Canada & UK institutions representatives and International Office Admissions staff
- Selected as IDP Malaysia's US Champion and Knowledge Management Specialist
- Selected as IDP Malaysia's IELTS, ISAT and AEAS tests Invigilator and Administrator
- Successful 2 days mass recruitment for Le Méridien Kota Kinabalu, Sabah with Le Meridien managers and expatriate managers hotels around South East Asia
- Successfully managed the HR Department operations as a new hotel (before hotel was fully operational and officially open) with HR Managers and Regional Director of Training from A Royal Meridien Plaza Athenee Bangkok and Le Meridien Kuala Lumpur
- Successful HR & induction training with HR Managers and Regional Director of Training from A Royal Meridien Plaza Athenee Bangkok and Le Meridien Kuala Lumpur
- Successful pre-opening event of Le Méridien Kota Kinabalu as a Pioneer Team Member
- Best Staff of the Quarter under the recognition program STAR OF THE QUARTER
- Managed high volumes of staff for Le Méridien Kota Kinabalu

#### Experience

# Present

Freelancer (HR Generalist)

Provide consulting services in all HR spectrum

**Home Based Tutor (part-time)** 

Tutors Bahasa Malaysia and English languages to Primary and Secondary students, tutors Mathematics to Primary 1 -3 students, assist with homework and revision for exams, educational consulting for study options and career advise for college or university

Aug 2011 - Aug 2016

Yayasan Sabah/Innoprise Corporation Sdn Bhd, Sabah, Malaysia (Secondment at Aquatica Aquarium & Discovery Centre Sdn Bhd)

Human Resources & Administration Executive (Senior Management Level)

Responsible and manage whole spectrum of HR and office administration ensuring HR and Administration's objective is achieved

- Part of the New Management Team
- Manage staff and daily office administration

- Support and assist Manager with overall business direction, operations, management and financial matters, implementation and enforcing of policies and procedures and Company's general terms and conditions
- Monitor, manage and plan staffing, payroll, training and learning and development programs, compensation and benefit programs and orientation or induction programs
- Employee relations managing absenteeism, disciplinary matters, handle grievances and provide counselling
- Manage employment contracts and issuance of employment contracts and other HR and Administration correspondence letters, roster scheduling
- Recruitment and retention, coordinate & conduct interviews and reference checks, exit interviews, performance evaluation and confirmation of new employees
- Coordinate and manage part-time employees and practical trainees
- Coordinate staff activities and gatherings
- Coordinate the Safety & Health Committee, Meetings, Programs and Policies based on HQ's requirements and Company's Business's requirements
- Liaise with relevant statutory bodies and agencies on various employment matters and legislations and financial institutions
- Liaise with Yayasan Sabah/ICSB on HR and Legal matters
- Liaise with Company Chairman and Board of Directors on Company matters and BOD meetings
- Liaise with Company Secretary on company matters and BOD meetings
- Liaise with both internal and external auditors of the Company
- Manage staff's personal files and leave records
- Manage and assist in work permit applications and cancellations for work permits for West Malaysian, Sarawakian and Expatriate employees
- Prepare & update reports and documentations for immigration
- Prepare & update reports on HR matters e.g. staffing budget, staffing matters
- Prepare & update reports and documentations as required by Manager
- Prepare reports and documentations as required by the Company Chairman
- ❖ Prepare BOD meeting papers for Company Secretary and Company Chairman
- \* Ad-hoc duties and tasks from the Company Chairman and Manager
- Assist Accounts Officer with issuance of invoices and vouchers, purchase orders, work orders, payments, data entry transactions in accounting system and generating reports from accounting system; when necessary and required in the absence of the Accounts Officer

# 2007 - 2011

# IDP Education Pty Ltd (Australia), Sabah Malaysia *Education Consultant (Senior Level)*

Counsel, advise and provide essential information, assess, monitor and guide students and parents for overseas studies (e.g. Australia, US, UK, Canada, New Zealand)

- IDP Malaysia Knowledge Management Specialist
- IDP Malaysia US Champion
- ❖ IELTS, ISAT and AEAS Invigilator and Administrator
- Co-manage daily Kota Kinabalu office branch operations and administration
- Counsel students and parents on the various programs
- Procedures of application assessment and submission to institutions
- Assistance with institutions' and accommodation applications and student visa applications
- Maintain and update student's database system, assess and monitor student's application and educational progress
- Update and manage IDP Malaysia Knowledge Management database
- Create awareness and promote IELTS testing and other supplementary tests
- Management & invigilation for IELTS, external tests and other supplementary tests
- Organize various education exhibitions, graduations and institutional visits
- Prepare, design and deliver talks & seminars at local institutions and schools
- Interact and maintain good relationships with overseas institution's representatives during visits, interview sessions and or exhibitions in Malaysia and overseas
- Interact and maintain good relationships with International Office-Admissions of institutions
- Interact and maintain good relationships with other educational agents
- Extend knowledge of institutions during familiarization visits overseas or and university representatives visits to IDP Education offices

# Le Méridien Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia Human Resources Coordinator (Mid Junior Level)

Responsible in all aspects of HR to ensure HR department's quality objective is achieved

- Coordinate, manage & plan HR activities and daily operations & administration
- Implement & enforce HR policies & procedures
- Monitor and conduct training & development programs
- Coordinate & conduct recruitment and selection activities
- Conduct interviews and reference checks
- Organise, design, manage and deliver orientation or induction programs
- \* Assist managing staff discipline issues, handle staff grievances and provide counselling
- Constant interaction with multi-racial employees of various levels both locals and foreigners (expatriates)
- Coordinate & organise staff gatherings, events and sport activities
- Manage employment contracts and issuance of employment contracts and other correspondence letters
- Coordinate & conduct on performance evaluation/appraisal and confirmation of new recruits within the probation period
- Coordinate & organise temporary/casual staff and practical trainees
- Maintain & update staff's personal records
- Manage & update various leave reports e.g. annual leave, sick leave, attendance etc
- Assist in work permit applications and accommodation issues for Expatriates, Sarawakian and West Malaysian staff
- Manage & update reports and documentations for immigration purposes
- Manage & update reports and documentations of food handlers matters
- Issuance of hotel's properties
- Liaise with relevant department's heads, assistants and staff
- Liaise with Finance department on payroll and salary increment & payment

# 2004 - 2005

# Karambunai Resorts Golf Club, Sabah, Malaysia Membership Services Executive (Mid Junior Level)

Responsible in the golf memberships and membership processes and activities

- Compile and maintain accurate and up-to-date records and ledgers of members
- Coordinate member's meetings, activities, tournaments
- Responsible for affiliation arrangements with other golf clubs in Malaysia
- Handle members queries and complaints
- Assist Club Manager and Sales & Marketing Manager maximize members' satisfaction with added services and feedbacks

#### Skills

Written and oral fluency in English and Malay languages

Proficient in general office duties and knowledge of Microsoft Office and UBS Accounting program Customer service skills and people management and development skills Communication and human relation skills

# Education

- 2004 Bachelor of Business (Human Resource Management & Management), La Trobe University, Melbourne, Australia
- 1999 United States Transfer Program, Kinabalu Commercial College, Sabah, Malaysia
- 1995 Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia, St. Francis Convent Secondary School, Sabah, Malaysia

## Interests

Reading, listening to music, watching movies and dramas

## **Trainings Attended**

- 1. Industrial First Aid & CPR
- 2. Fire fighting & Evacuation Training
- 3. Bio-Net System
- 4. HRMWin & TMSWin Systems
- 5. Commitment to Excellence
- 6. Starwood Preferred Guest
- 7. FCS-Engineering System
- 8. Quality Awareness training
- 9. STAR Training
- 10. Salesforce CRM Training
- 11. PRISMS Training
- 12. IELTS, ISAT, AEAS test administration and invigilation training
- 13. OSCAR Training
- 14. UBS Accounting
- 15. Food Handlers Course
- 16. Basic Conversational Mandarin Level 1 (3 months)

## Activities

President, Australian Degree Student Society, Nilai International College, Malaysia

**Secretary, English Language Society**, Nilai International College, Malaysia

President, Volleyball Club, St. Francis Convent Secondary School, Malaysia

Director of Photography, Magazine Board, St. Francis Convent Secondary School, Malaysia

**Ordinary Member,** Australian Human Resources Institute

Member, La Trobe University Alumni, Melbourne Australia

Member, Nilai University College Alumni, Negeri Sembilan Malaysia Secretary, Safety & Health Committee, Le Méridien Kota Kinabalu

Committee Member, Sabah Australian Alumni Association, Kota Kinabalu (2008-2009)

Member, Sabah Australian Alumni Association, Kota Kinabalu

# Salary

Last drawn salary: RM 4,800.00++

Expected salary : RM 4,500.00 - 5,500.00 (negotiable)

## References

Name: Cynthia Celestine
Telephone: (61) 3 9612 4512
Email: cynthia.celestine@idp.com
Operational Improvements Manager
IDP Education Pty Ltd, Melbourne, Australia
(Previous Country Director- Malaysia)
IDP Education Pty Ltd, Melbourne, Australia

Name: Chua Soon Choo Telephone: (60) 03 - 3319 2811

(60) 12 - 278 6187 (Mobile)

Email: <a href="mailto:soonchoo.chua@unsw.edu.au">soonchoo.chua@unsw.edu.au</a> Regional Manager (Malaysia)

**UNSW Malaysia** 

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

(Previous Senior Manager – Malaysia

IDP Education Pty Ltd, Subang Jaya, Malaysia)

Name: Supamit Kosintraporn Telephone: (66) 2 - 126 9999

Email: <a href="mailto:supamit-kosintraporn@yahoo.com">supamit-kosintraporn@yahoo.com</a>

Human Resources Manager

Sofitel Bangkok Sukhumvit, Bangkok, Thailand (Previous Human Resources Manager of A Royal Méridien Plaza Athenee Bangkok,

Bangkok, Thailand)

Name: Norman bin Ramlee @ Ramli Telephone: (60) 19 - 536 8838 (Mobile)

Manager

Aquatica Aquarium & Discovery Centre Sdn Bhd

Kota Kinabalu, Sabah, Malaysia